<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
    <BedOwnershipTools.EnableCommunalBeds>Enable communal beds</BedOwnershipTools.EnableCommunalBeds>
    <BedOwnershipTools.EnableCommunalBeds_Tooltip>If enabled, beds can be flagged for communal use.\n\nColonists who cannot access an assigned bed will try to sleep in an accessible communal bed with higher priority than the ground. Colonists won't relinquish existing bed assignments when they sleep in a communal bed.</BedOwnershipTools.EnableCommunalBeds_Tooltip>
    <BedOwnershipTools.CommunalBedsSupportOrderedMedicalSleep>Communal beds support ordered medical sleep</BedOwnershipTools.CommunalBedsSupportOrderedMedicalSleep>
    <BedOwnershipTools.CommunalBedsSupportOrderedMedicalSleep_Tooltip>If enabled with the communal bed feature, colonists may be ordered via a right-click action to use a communal bed as a target for medical sleep.\n\n(Note that regardless of this option's setting, communal beds are valid medical sleep locations ranked below medical beds in automatic search priority.)</BedOwnershipTools.CommunalBedsSupportOrderedMedicalSleep_Tooltip>

    <BedOwnershipTools.EnableBedAssignmentPinning>Enable bed assignment pinning</BedOwnershipTools.EnableBedAssignmentPinning>
    <BedOwnershipTools.EnableBedAssignmentPinning_Tooltip>If enabled, beds can be flagged as having pinned ownership.\n\nWhen a colonist is assigned to such a bed, they will not sleep in another bed if such an action would result in loss of the pinned assignment. Only player action and major story events (death, separation, abduction, etc.) can cause loss of a pinned bed assignment.</BedOwnershipTools.EnableBedAssignmentPinning_Tooltip>
    <BedOwnershipTools.PawnsMaySelfAssignToUnownedPinnedBeds>Colonists may self-assign to vacant spots on pinned beds</BedOwnershipTools.PawnsMaySelfAssignToUnownedPinnedBeds>
    <BedOwnershipTools.PawnsMaySelfAssignToUnownedPinnedBeds_Tooltip>If enabled with the pinnable bed assignment feature, colonists may self-assign to unowned or partner-owned beds flagged as having a pinned owner.\n\nThey would become a pinned owner of such a bed once self-assigned. If disabled, only player action can cause a colonist to gain a pinned bed assignment.</BedOwnershipTools.PawnsMaySelfAssignToUnownedPinnedBeds_Tooltip>

    <BedOwnershipTools.EnableBedAssignmentGroups>Enable multiple bed assignment system</BedOwnershipTools.EnableBedAssignmentGroups>
    <BedOwnershipTools.EnableBedAssignmentGroups_Tooltip>If enabled, allows beds to be categorized by the player into assignment groups.\n\nColonists may own at most one bed in each assignment group. When a colonist is tired, they will try to sleep in the bed of the most prioritized group that they can access. If pinned ownership is enabled, pinning only takes effect only within the beds of a group.\n\nDisabling this toggle will cause inactive bed assignments to be cleared.</BedOwnershipTools.EnableBedAssignmentGroups_Tooltip>

    <BedOwnershipTools.ShowCommunalGUIOverlayInsteadOfBlankUnderBed>Show "communal" label instead of blank under bed</BedOwnershipTools.ShowCommunalGUIOverlayInsteadOfBlankUnderBed>
    <BedOwnershipTools.ShowCommunalGUIOverlayInsteadOfBlankUnderBed_Tooltip>If enabled with the communal bed feature, vacant communal beds will indicate their owner as "(comm.)" over the bed. If disabled, communal beds will not display anything where "Unowned" would normally be shown.\n\n(Note that regardless of this setting, bed settings can be inspected by clicking on the bed.)</BedOwnershipTools.ShowCommunalGUIOverlayInsteadOfBlankUnderBed_Tooltip>
    <BedOwnershipTools.HideGUIOverlayOnNonHumanlikeBeds>Hide GUI overlay on animal beds</BedOwnershipTools.HideGUIOverlayOnNonHumanlikeBeds>
    <BedOwnershipTools.HideGUIOverlayOnNonHumanlikeBeds_Tooltip>If enabled, animal beds will not show labels over the bed indicating communal, pinned, or assignment group information. Enabling this option will hide communal labels, overriding the "Show 'communal' label instead of blank under bed" option.\n\n(Note that regardless of this setting, bed settings can be inspected by clicking on the bed.)</BedOwnershipTools.HideGUIOverlayOnNonHumanlikeBeds_Tooltip>
    <BedOwnershipTools.ShowColonistsAcrossAllMapsInAssignmentDialog>Show global colony member list while assigning beds</BedOwnershipTools.ShowColonistsAcrossAllMapsInAssignmentDialog>
    <BedOwnershipTools.ShowColonistsAcrossAllMapsInAssignmentDialog_Tooltip>If enabled, bed assignment dialogs will show eligible pawns across all maps, caravans and transporters. If disabled, reverts to vanilla behaviour where only pawns on the bed's map are shown.</BedOwnershipTools.ShowColonistsAcrossAllMapsInAssignmentDialog_Tooltip>

    <BedOwnershipTools.EnableHospitalityModCompatPatches>Enable Hospitality mod compatibility patches</BedOwnershipTools.EnableHospitalityModCompatPatches>
    <BedOwnershipTools.EnableModCompatPatches_Tooltip>Enables patching code within another mod, to improve compatibility with this mod. If enabled, only takes effect if that mod is loaded.\n\nThese patches may break with updates from either mod. This toggle allows opt-out from these code patches, as they may not be required for a playable experience.\n\nRimWorld must be restarted for a toggle to take effect.</BedOwnershipTools.EnableModCompatPatches_Tooltip>

    <BedOwnershipTools.DevEnableDebugInspectStringListings>[DEV] Enable debug inspect string listings</BedOwnershipTools.DevEnableDebugInspectStringListings>
    <BedOwnershipTools.DevEnableDebugInspectStringListings_Tooltip>Enables displaying reference identifiers and ownership lists on Building_Beds and Pawns in-game on the inspector panel, to assist with debugging ownership state.</BedOwnershipTools.DevEnableDebugInspectStringListings_Tooltip>
    <BedOwnershipTools.DevEnableUnaccountedCaseLogging>[DEV] Enable unaccounted case logging</BedOwnershipTools.DevEnableUnaccountedCaseLogging>
    <BedOwnershipTools.DevEnableUnaccountedCaseLogging_Tooltip>Enables printing warnings when a pawn is asked to unclaim one of its beds by a caller that is not aware of the multiple bed ownership system. In such cases, without special handling, the pawn would unclaim all its beds.</BedOwnershipTools.DevEnableUnaccountedCaseLogging_Tooltip>
</LanguageData>
